Don't believe the fairy tale.
Maleficent is a fantasy, adventure, action film directed by Robert Stromberg.
A beautiful, pure-hearted young woman, Maleficent has an idyllic life growing up in a peaceable
forest kingdom, until one day when an invading army threatens the harmony of the land.
She rises to be the land's fiercest protector, but she ultimately suffers a
ruthless betrayal – an act that begins to turn her heart into stone.
Bent on revenge, Maleficent faces an epic battle with the invading King's successor
and, as a result, places a curse upon his newborn infant Aurora.
As the child grows, Maleficent realizes that Aurora holds the key to peace
in the kingdom – and to Maleficent's true happiness as well.
Maleficent, played by Angelina Jolie.
Princess Aurora, played by Elle Fanning.
Knotgrass, played by Imelda Staunton.
Stefan, played by Sharlto Copley.
Flittle, played by Lesley Manville.
Thistletwit, played by Juno Temple.
Maleficent is a 2014 American fantasy film starring Angelina Jolie as the title character in a live-action retelling of her
villainous role in Walt Disney's 1959 animated film Sleeping Beauty, itself an adaptation of the 1697 fairy tale.
The film was directed by Robert Stromberg and written by Linda Woolverton.
It also stars Sharlto Copley, Elle Fanning, Sam Riley, Imelda
Staunton, Juno Temple, and Lesley Manville.
Maleficent was originally developed as an animated project in 2003, before it was changed
to a live-action feature in 2006, following Disney's acquisition of Pixar.
Tim Burton was originally attached to direct the film, but was
replaced by Stromberg in his directorial debut.
Jolie signed on to play the title role in January 2012 and
also served as the film's executive producer.
The rest of the main cast joined between March and May 2012.
Principal photography took place at Pinewood Studios in
Buckinghamshire, England, from June to October 2012.
Maleficent premiered in El Capitan Theatre in Hollywood on May 28, 2014, and was released in
the United States theatrically on May 30 by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures.
It received mixed reviews from critics and was a commercial success, grossing over $758
million worldwide and becoming the fourth-highest-grossing film of 2014.
It received an Academy Award nomination for Best
Costume Design at the 87th Academy Awards.
A sequel, Maleficent: Mistress of Evil, was released in 2019.
The film explores themes of friendship, magic, kingdom, fairy tale, fairy.
The tone is dark and emotional.